RG 110, Monday Afternoon Club
Connecticut State Library
Monday Afternoon Club records
1887-1938
Connecticut State Library
Monday Afternoon Club (Hartford, Conn.)
0.5 cubic feet
The Monday Afternoon Club was organized on January 4, 1886. The main objective of the society was “the study of history-not general nor in consecutive course, but the selection of certain periods determined by vote of members.”
RG110
T001446
Historical Note
The Monday Afternoon Club was organized on January 4, 1886. The main objective of the society was “the study of history-not general nor in consecutive course, but the selection of certain periods determined by vote of members.”
Scope and Content
Records include meeting minutes, correspondence, memorials to deceased members, and a short history of the group’s 50th anniversary (1936).
Related Material
The Connecticut Historical Society has two handwritten sketches by Elizabeth L. Dixon read before the club in 1901 and 1903. The former is entitled, "Green and Cornwallis: the war in the southern department," and the latter is entitled, "Abraham Lincoln and His Policy."
Index Terms
Organizations:
Monday Afternoon Club (Hartford, Conn.)
Subjects:
Clubs -- Connecticut -- Hartford; Women -- Connecticut -- Hartford -- Societies and clubs; Monday Afternoon Club (Hartford, Conn.) -- Records and correspondence
Document Types:
Minutes; Correspondence
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1887-1938
  - 1. Minutes, 1887-1890, 1902-1938; 7 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1887-1890, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1902-1907, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1907-1909, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1909-1916, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1916-1926, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1926-1933, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1933-1938, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - 2. Miscellaneous papers of the club, circa 1930-1936; 1 folder (Box 1)
    This group of records includes a discussion of the history, objectives and rules of the club, the order of business at meetings, memorials to deceased members, and a short history written by Mar Monteith Keller in 1936, the 50th year anniversary.